A Guide to the Facilities Management Architectural Drawings 1914-1983: UA 0047
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Facilities Management Architectural Drawings,
1914-1983
Special Collections, James Madison University
UA 0047
0.5 cubic feet; 2 folders
The Facilities Management Architectural Drawings 1914-1983, are comprised of blue prints, pencil tracings, and linen drawings of various James Madison University buildings, their corresponding mechanical systems, and campus grounds.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from JMU's Facilities Management Engineering Department in 2006.
Provenance
The Harrisonburg High School (now Memorial Hall) drawings became property of James Madison University after the university purchased the high school in 2006.
Bio/Historical Note
Due to the nature of this collection, a historical note is not applicable. Patrons are encouraged to refer to the bibliography for further historical information pertaining to specific James Madison University campus buildings included in the collection.
Scope and Content
Facilities Management Architectural Drawings, 1914-1983, are comprised of blueprints, pencil tracings, and linen drawings of various JMU buildings, their corresponding mechanical systems, floor plans, and campus grounds. The collection contains architectural plans of Alumnae Hall, Dormitory #5, Harrisonburg High School (currently Memorial Hall), the Home Economics Building (currently Moody Hall), Miller Hall, the Practice House (currently Varner House), the Students' Building (currently Harrison Hall), and topographic drawings of Madison College. The plans were created on four different surfaces: pencil on linen, ink on linen, pencil on tracing paper, and carbon copy paper.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by the building name listed on the drawing and then separated by material type. Items that are undersized or of a fragile nature are housed in subfolders.
Bibliography
Dingledine, Raymond C. Madison College: The First Fifty Years, 1908-1958. Harrisonburg, VA.: James Madison University, 1959.
James Madison University. "JMU Centennial Celebration - Major Buildings." Accessed 2010. http://www.jmu.edu/centennialcelebration/major_buildings.shtml.
Jones, Nancy Bondurant. Rooted on Bluestone Hill: A History of James Madison University. Santa Fe and Staunton, Va.: Center for American Places, 2004.
Index Terms
Subjects:
James Madison University -- History; Madison College -- History; State Teachers College at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; James Madison University -- Buildings; Madison College -- Buildings; State Teachers College at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- Buildings; State Normal School for Women at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- Buildings; Education, Higher -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History; Architecture -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Maps (documents); Blueprints (reprographic copies)
- Alumnae Hall, Front Elevation, May 1, 1921 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Architect: Charles M. Robinson Material Type: ink on linen
- Dormitory #5, Front Elevation, April 1, 1926 (Box 3, Drawer 2)
  Architect: Charles M. Robinson Material Type: blueprint
- Harrisonburg High School, Smoke Pipe Harrisonburg, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  Architect: unknown Material Type: tracing, pencil
- Harrisonburg High School, Plan Showing the Position of Motor Base, April 26, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  Architect: American Heating and Ventilating Company Material Type: tracing, pencil
- Harrisonburg High School, Section Thru Fan Room Showing Fresh Air Partition, April 4, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  Architect: L. W. L. Material Type: tracing, pencil
- Harrisonburg High School, End View Showing Partition in Suspended Ceiling over Vent Shaft, April 27, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
- Harrisonburg High School, Detail Showing Position of Ducts in Plenum Space, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
- Harrisonburg High School, Plan of a Six-Stall Urinal, December 23, 1927 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
- Home Economics Building, Basement Floor Plan, November 20, 1958 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  Architect: Walford and Wright Material Type: blueprint
- Home Economics Building, First Floor Plan, November 20, 1958 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Second Floor Plan, November 20, 1958 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Front Elevation, November 20, 1958 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Left-Side Elevation; Rear Elevation, November 20, 1958 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory No.1 Layout, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory No. 3 Layout, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory 203, March 28, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory 203, March 28, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory 201, March 28, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Floor Plan Food Lab #201, March 29, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory 202, March 31, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Food Laboratory 202, March 31, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Kitchen 211, October 6, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Textile Laboratory 109, October 6, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Related Arts Classroom No. 20, October 10, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Clothing Laboratory 107, October 10, 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Basement Floor Plan; First Floor Plan; Finish Schedule; Door Schedule, June 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Second Floor Plan; Attic & Roof Plan; etc., June 1960 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Basement Floor Plan, June 19, 1969 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  Architect: D'earcy P. Davis and Associates, Clyde E. McClintock Material Type: blueprint
- Home Economics Building, Floor Plan, June 9, 1969 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Equipment & Utility Schedule, June 9, 1969 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Lounge, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Building, Room 210, 212, 213, 217, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Madison College, Control Surveys and Monuments, March 26, 1940 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  Architect: Comm. Virginia...Section of Institutional Engineering Material Type: blueprint
- Madison College, Madison College, undated (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  Architect: Va State Planning Board Material Type: blueprint
- Madison College, Topography, Madison College, April 1, 1940 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Madison College, Topography, Madison College, April 1, 1940 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)
- Miller Hall, Miller Hall completion - East End; Entrance at Southeast corner of building, March 3, 1983 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  Architect: Drawn by D.P.D. Material Type: linen, pencil
- Miller Hall, Miller Hall completion - East End; Details, March 3, 1983 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
- Miller Hall, Miller Hall completion - East End; Elevation and Section, March 3, 1983 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 1)
- Practice House, Basement Plan, May 5, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2A)
- Practice House, First Floor Plan, May 5, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2A)
- Practice House, Second Floor Plan, May 5, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2A)
- Practice House, Attic Plan, May 5, 1928 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2A)
- Students' Building, Front and Side Elevation, April 1, 1914 (Box 3, Drawer 2, Folder 2)